Finding Aid for Ronald R. Stockton papers, 1960s-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ronald R. Stockton papers 1960s-2014
Stockton, Ronald R.
2 linear feet (in 3 boxes)
2012043 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received from Professor Stockton (donor no. 10572 ) in June 2011 and in June 2014.
Periodic additions to the papers are expected.
The Millennium Journal in box 1 is closed to research until 2025 or the death of the author, whichever comes first. The writings in box 2 are open without restriction.
Ronald R. Stockton is a professor of political science at the University of Michigan-Dearborn. He writes and teaches about the role of religion and religious values in the United States and abroad. Many of his writings relate to Arab American relations, especially in the Detroit area. Other writings concern comparative non-western politics, especially ethnic conflict, political change, and the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.
The Ronald R. Stockton collection consists of various writings, most on topics relating to his research and teaching interests. These topics include Arab American relations, religion, historical and genealogical subjects, and articles about Kenya.
In 2000, Ronald Stockton began a journal which was intended to be read by his descendents. In it, he wrote of his daily activities interspersed with reflections on current events. In his journal, Stockton wrote of his daily activities interspersed with reflections on current events. This journal dates from 2000 to 2005 and continues with 2010. This journal is currently closed to research until 2025.
Subjects:
Stockton, Ronald R.; Arab Americans--Michigan.; University of Michigan-Dearborn--Faculty.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.
- Writings
  - "Life in the Year 2000; A Millennium Journal for My Descendents in the Year 2100" (Box 1)
    [Restricted: Closed to research until 2025 or death of author whichever comes first
  - Updates to Millennium Journal, 2001-2005 and 2010 (Box 1)
  - Articles about Stockton, 1991-2011 (Box 2)
  - Books by Stockton
    - Decent and in Order: Conflict, Christianity, and Polity in a Presbyterian Congregation, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Horse Prairie Cemetery, Sesser, Illinois: Tombstone Inscriptions and Family Records, 2004 (Box 2)
    - A Time of Turmoil: Values and Voting in the 1970s, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Book Reviews, 1975-2009 (Box 2)
  - Journal Articles/Papers, 1968-2014, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Journal Articles/Papers, 1968-2014, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Manuscript: "Development and Discontent: A Study of Social Mobilization in the Nyeri District of Kenya," undated (Box 3)
  - Talks, 1997-2014 (Box 3)